um okay markdown markdown why not Mark
up this is going to seem backwards or
upside down because we're going to learn
markdown before
markup and I just want to break down the
way that we're going to approach
markdown in a single video up front so
you can decide if you're interested in
getting into this or not if you're not
fine but if you are here's how we're
going to first of all understand the
history and purpose of markdown where it
came from what problem it was solving
who made it Etc then we're going to
learn a simplified standardized version
of markdown that will get quite
interesting when we talk about where it
came from and how hard it has been to
standardize u in fact some would say it
still hasn't been standardized we will
pick one specific type of very
customized markdown called GitHub
flavored markdown and we'll talk about
why that should be the one that you
learn uh above all others in my opinion
and then we'll briefly touch on some
terms you might hear latch and math
Jacks and when to use them and why you
would care uh we are not going to learn
those Technologies right now but you
you'll know when to use them and where
to go use them some of you will have a
very specific need for that and um which
is you know fundamentally the reason
that we're using GTO flavor markdown um
um at least one person is like wait
aren't we already aren't we going to
learn
pandoc um well I guess we should say use
pandoc should we do
that uh experiment uh with pandok so
pandok is an amazing Tool uh that helps
you to leverage all these other things
uh we should probably also experiment
with make Docks but we will not do that
in fact let's uh let's make that an
extra how about that experiment with
make dos you can't quite experiment with
make dos until you get a command line
access which you don't have yet so I'm
going to get rid of that take it back I
take it all back I'm so sorry I forgot
you haven't learned it you haven't
learned the pandoc is amazing um you
haven't learned the terminal yet so when
you learn a terminal we can do all of
those things and we can revisit that we
can come back and use some of those cool
Technologies right now we're going to be
learning markdown without any need for
anything special on your computer yeah
and let's talk about that now